Jack Fischer

💻 Full-Stack Web Developer. 📤 Occasional Adventurer. 革 Big Fan of Garlic Naan.

Address: Remote/Miami Beach, FL | Email: letsbuild@jackbuildstech.com

Personal Site: https://jackbuildstech.com | GitHub: https://github.com/sunspla-sh

Summary

I enjoy growing and scaling web applications with Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD pipelines, Unit and E2E Testing, RESTful APIs or GraphQL, preferably Node.js or other JavaScript runtimes on the backend, preferably React on the frontend although I'm open to other SPA libraries and frameworks.

Visit my personal site https://jackbuildstech.com for a summary of my projects and experience or watch my video resume: https://youtu.be/ERXwTo-zWig

Experience

Full Stack Web Development Instructor

Mar 2022 - Jan 2023

Ironhack (https://ironhack.com)

- My former students collectively earn roughly \$800,000-1,000,000 in annual income as junior web developers (or similar tech jobs) with an average salary in the \$50,000-60,000 range (representing a 50-100% increase in annual income for most of them, because they primarily came from a hospitality or retail service background)
- Taught 4 cohorts of students to use modern, full stack web development technologies such as the following: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, Express, Handlebars, Databases (MongoDB), ODMs (Mongoose), Single-page Applications (React), Version Control (Git and Github), Unit Testing (Jest), Deployment, etc.

Failed Startups - Multiple Attempts

Aug 2020 - Feb 2022

Failed Startups

- Rejected from YCombinator with first idea the idea was capital-intensive and we had no clear path forward (and no cash), so my co-founders returned to their jobs
- Continued on solo with second idea scuba diving booking software-as-a-service - I tried to be smarter this time and pre-sell based on UX/UI wireframes before fully coding it, but failed to find product-market fit (basically I ran out of savings)

Playa Del Carmen (Mexico)

- Studied Spanish in Mexico to a tested level of CEFR Level B1 Intermediate (Level B1 is high enough to gain entrance to some
 universities in Spain such as <u>Universidad Complutense Madrid</u> while
 others require B2)
- Spanish exam credential can be independently verified at the following website (https://siele.org/en/comprobar-certificado) using my credential ID: li3knEHpdbkjrFuagvJ7RA==

Front-End Web Developer (Contractor)

Apr 2019 - Jul 2020

Carnival Cruise Line (https://carnival.com)

- Built various front end sections of the carnival.com site including updated versions of the checkout review page within the booking engine, mobile menu, modals, banners, sliders etc
- A/B tested code and toggled features using Optimizely to verify that newly coded sections of the site increased overall customer conversions/revenue
- Hired and managed 4 employees/subcontractors doing frontend web development, UX/UIi design, and data analytics, who were billed under me and worked alongside me at Carnival

Projects (Practice & Personal)

1) JobAppTrack.com (Web Application and Chrome Extension)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/simple-job-app-tracker-react)
Technologies Used:

Docker, Vite, React, CSS, JavaScript, Prisma, SQLite, Node.js, Express, Nodemailer, Handlebars, Open Graph Protocol, CRXJS, pnpm, TurboRepo, Socket.io (Websockets), Fly.io

2) GitBoxDraw.com (Web Application)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/github-commit-text-generator)

Technologies Used:

Vite, Sass, HTML, JavaScript, Open Graph Protocol, Node.js, Rollup, JavaScript Obfuscator (Rollup Plugin), npm, DigitalOcean

3) IPomg.com (Web Application)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/ipomg-static)

Technologies Used:

Vite, TailwindCSS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MaxMind GeoLite2 DB, Node.js, Express, npm, DigitalOcean

4) CommandLineCartography (Script)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/command-line-cartography-practice)

Technologies Used:

D3, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, pnpm, U.S. Census Bureau Data

5) S Tier Web Dev (Web Dev Tutorials - YouTube Channel)

(https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgF6apjFR90209B4006e8qpNV7qUC-bUD)

Technologies Used:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Various Recording and Editing Software (Kdenlive, OBS, GIMP, YoutubeStudio, Podia)

6) NFL Team Data Scraper (Script)

(https://github.com/sunspla-sh/nfl-team-data-scraper)

Technologies Used:

Puppeteer, Node.js, npm

Tech Skills and Theory

Front-End Web Development

JavaScript, Single-page Applications (React), GraphQL, HTML, CSS, SASS, TailwindCSS, Mobile-first (Responsive) Design, D3, Vite, Chrome Extensions (CRXJS), npm, pnpm, Open Graph Protocol, Websockets (Socket.io)

Back-End Web Development

Node.js, Web Application Frameworks and APIs (Express), Databases (MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQLite), ODMs and ORMs (Mongoose, Sequelize, Prisma), GraphQL, Unit Testing (Jest), Puppeteer, Nodemailer, Email Templating (Handlebars), Websockets (Socket.io), MVC architecture, npm, pnpm, GeoJSON, TopoJSON, JSON, XML

DevOps and Tooling

Version Control (Git), CI/CD (TravisCI), Cloud Infrastructure (DigitalOcean, AWS, Fly.io, Heroku), Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Monorepos, Bundlers and Build Systems (TurboRepo, Rollup), Postman

Other Skills

Languages:

English (Native),

Spanish (CEFR - Level B1 - SIELE - <u>Credential ID li3knEHpdbkjrFuagvJ7RA==</u>), Russian (CEFR - Level A1)

Video and Image Editing:

Kdenlive (Video Editing), OBS (Video recording and livestreaming) GIMP (Image Editing)

Education

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp - Ironhack

Jan 2019 - Mar 2019

10-week intensive (400+ hour) web development boot camp which complimented my existing computer science skills from some of my university classes

Study Abroad - Moscow State University

May 2016 - Aug 2016

I like learning languages. I studied Russian language and culture during a summer abroad and visited various cities in Russia.

Liberal Studies, B.A. - Iowa State University

Aug 2014 - Jun 2018

I should have been focused on building technical skills instead of "following my passion" and taking a bunch of random liberal arts classes. Fortunately, younger me decided to fill some elective classes with computer science subjects, which led to my current career.